Guide to the Frederick R. Koch Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Frederick R. Koch collection
1640-1983
GEN MSS 601
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
65.12
(368 boxes) + 1 art, 4 broadside
The Frederick R. Koch Collection consists of musical, literary, and historical materials collected by Frederick R. Koch, principally through purchases at public auctions, 1979-1986. Including individual items, concentrations of related materials, and several extensive archives, the collection is a broad and deep resource for study of the lives and works of a range of composers, authors, and other historical figures. Most materials are music manuscripts, literary manuscripts, drawings, and correspondence of European, English, and American composers, authors, and artists. Also present are historical manuscripts, photographs, albums, and other papers. While the contents of the collection span the seventeenth to twentieth centuries, most date from the nineteenth to early twentieth centuries, with particular strengths in French, Italian, German, and British music, French literature, and British art.
Koch, Frederick R. (Frederick Robinson)
Frederick R. Koch Foundation
Balfe, M. W. (Michael William), 1808-1870 ( Dʹi︠a︡volina)
Bantock, Granville, Sir, 1868-1946 ( Songs, Selections)
Berlioz, Hector, 1803-1869 ( Grande ouverture du Roi Lear)
Berners, Gerald Hugh Tyrwhitt-Wilson, Baron, 1883-1950 ( Triumph of Neptune)
Boccherini, Luigi, 1743-1805 ( Quintets, piano, strings, G. 413-418)
Brahms, Johannes, 1833-1897 ( Gesänge, op. 72, Alte Liebe)
Brahms, Johannes, 1833-1897 ( Freiwillige her!)
Brahms, Johannes, 1833-1897 ( Gebt Acht!)
Brahms, Johannes, 1833-1897 ( Jetzt habe ich schon)
Chaminade, Cécile, 1857-1944 ( Chanson slave)
Chopin, Frédéric, 1810-1849 ( Cantabile, piano, B. 84, B♭ major)
Cocteau, Jean, 1889-1963 ( Mariés de la tour Eiffel)
Coward, Noel, 1899-1973 ( Present indicative)
Cox, Palmer, 1840-1924 ( Brownie calendar)
Daudet, Alphonse, 1840-1897 ( Arlésienne)
Debussy, Claude, 1862-1918 ( Ariettes oubliées, Chevaux de bois)
Debussy, Claude, 1862-1918 ( Ariettes oubliées, Ombre des arbres)
Debussy, Claude, 1862-1918 ( Colloque sentimental)
Debussy, Claude, 1862-1918 ( Intermezzi, cello, orchestra, C minor, arranged)
Debussy, Claude, 1862-1918 ( Jeux)
Debussy, Claude, 1862-1918 ( Pelléas & Mélisande)
Debussy, Claude, 1862-1918 ( 3 song cycles)
Dukas, Paul, 1865-1935 ( Fleur)
Dukas, Paul, 1865-1935 ( Polyeucte)
Dukas, Paul, 1865-1935 ( Velléda)
Dumas, Alexandre, 1824-1895 ( Dame aux camélias (Novel))
Dumas, Alexandre, 1824-1895 ( Dame aux camélias (Play))
Duparc, Henri, 1848-1933 ( Duparc album)
Dvořák, Antonín, 1841-1904 ( O sanctissima)
Elgar, Edward, 1857-1934 ( Part songs, op. 53, There is sweet music)
Falla, Manuel de, 1876-1946 ( A Córdoba)
Fauré, Gabriel, 1845-1924 ( Berceuse from the Dolly suite)
Fauré, Gabriel, 1845-1924 ( Mai)
Fauré, Gabriel, 1845-1924 ( Puisque j'ai mis ma lèvre)
Fauré, Gabriel, 1845-1924 ( Dream of love)
Fauré, Gabriel, 1845-1924 ( Sonatas, piano)
Franck, César, 1822-1890 ( Aimer)
Franck, César, 1822-1890 ( Béatitudes)
Genet, Jean, 1910-1986 ( Bonnes)
German, Edward, 1862-1936 ( Just so song book, Rolling down to Rio)
Giordano, Umberto, 1867-1948 ( Marina)
Glazunov, Aleksandr Konstantinovich, 1865-1936 ( Fantaisie finnoise)
Gounod, Charles, 1818-1893 ( George Dandin)
Gounod, Charles, 1818-1893 ( Doctor despite himself)
Guitry, Sacha, 1885-1957 ( Je t'aime)
Hahn, Reynaldo, 1875-1947 ( Feuilles blessée)
Hahn, Reynaldo, 1875-1947 ( Œuvres pour deux pianos)
Hahn, Reynaldo, 1875-1947 ( 5 mélodies choisies)
Halévy, F., 1799-1862 ( Tentation)
Handel, George Frideric, 1685-1759 ( Haec est Regina Virginum)
Handel, George Frideric, 1685-1759 ( 3 vesper Psalms, No. 2)
Handel, George Frideric, 1685-1759 ( Saeviat tellus)
Handel, George Frideric, 1685-1759 ( Te decus virgineum, HWV 243)
Hofmannsthal, Hugo von, 1874-1929 ( Elektra)
Hofmannsthal, Hugo von, 1874-1929 ( Märchen der 672. Nacht)
Ireland, John, 1879-1962 ( Forgotten rite)
Ireland, John, 1879-1962 ( Sea idyll)
Jerome, William Travers, 1850-1934 ( Famous hypothetical question in the trial of Harry K. Thaw for the murder of Stanford White)
Lear, Edward, 1812-1888 ( Book of nonsense)
Lecocq, Charles, 1832-1918 ( Figlia di Madama Angot)
Leoncavallo, Ruggiero, 1858-1919 ( A chi la giarrettiera?)
Leoncavallo, Ruggiero, 1858-1919 ( Ave Maria (Opera))
Leoncavallo, Ruggiero, 1858-1919 ( Coupe et les lèvres)
Leoncavallo, Ruggiero, 1858-1919 ( Écho)
Leoncavallo, Ruggiero, 1858-1919 ( Goffredo Mameli)
Leoncavallo, Ruggiero, 1858-1919 ( Maiá)
Leoncavallo, Ruggiero, 1858-1919 ( Malbruk)
Leoncavallo, Ruggiero, 1858-1919 ( Manicuring girl)
Leoncavallo, Ruggiero, 1858-1919 ( Pantins vivants)
Leoncavallo, Ruggiero, 1858-1919 ( Pierrot au cinéma)
Leoncavallo, Ruggiero, 1858-1919 ( Reginetta delle rose)
Leoncavallo, Ruggiero, 1858-1919 ( Roland)
Leoncavallo, Ruggiero, 1858-1919 ( Zazà)
Leoncavallo, Ruggiero, 1858-1919 ( Zingari)
Liszt, Franz, 1811-1886 ( Ballades, piano, no. 1, D♭ major)
Liszt, Franz, 1811-1886 ( Fantasie über Themen aus Webers Der Freischütz)
Liszt, Franz, 1811-1886 ( Für Männergesang, No. 4)
Liszt, Franz, 1811-1886 ( Für Männergesang, No. 5)
Liszt, Franz, 1811-1886 ( Concerto pathétique)
Liszt, Franz, 1811-1886 ( Ich möchte hingehn)
Liszt, Franz, 1811-1886 ( Dal az esthajnali csillaghoz)
Liszt, Franz, 1811-1886 ( Fantaisie brillante sur des motifs de l'opéra de Halévy)
Liszt, Franz, 1811-1886 ( Ergebung)
Liszt, Franz, 1811-1886 ( Marche hongroise, no. 2)
Louÿs, Pierre, 1870-1925 ( Chanson des rois mages)
Maclaren, Archibald, 1819-1884 ( Fairy family)
Mahler, Gustav, 1860-1911 ( Lieder und Gesänge aus der Jugendzeit, Starke Einbildungskraft)
Malibran, Maria, 1808-1836 ( Matelot)
Mascagni, Pietro, 1863-1945 ( Alla gioia)
Mascagni, Pietro, 1863-1945 ( Canzone popolare)
Mascagni, Pietro, 1863-1945 ( In filanda)
Mascagni, Pietro, 1863-1945 ( Inno ad Adelaide Cairoli)
Mascagni, Pietro, 1863-1945 ( Invocazione alla madonna)
Mascagni, Pietro, 1863-1945 ( Isabeau, Libretto)
Mascagni, Pietro, 1863-1945 ( Nerone)
Mascagni, Pietro, 1863-1945 ( Pinotta, Coro di Filatrici)
Mascagni, Pietro, 1863-1945 ( Sì)
Massenet, Jules, 1842-1912 ( Amadis, Libretto)
Massenet, Jules, 1842-1912 ( Bac)
Massenet, Jules, 1842-1912 ( Bacchus)
Massenet, Jules, 1842-1912 ( Chanson pour elle, arranged)
Massenet, Jules, 1842-1912 ( Cléopâtre)
Massenet, Jules, 1842-1912 ( Erinnyes)
Massenet, Jules, 1842-1912 ( Ève)
Massenet, Jules, 1842-1912 ( Fantaisie, cello, orchestra, D major)
Massenet, Jules, 1842-1912 ( Erodiade)
Massenet, Jules, 1842-1912 ( Jérusalem)
Massenet, Jules, 1842-1912 ( Marche solennelle)
Massenet, Jules, 1842-1912 ( Mienne!)
Massenet, Jules, 1842-1912 ( Panurge)
Massenet, Jules, 1842-1912 ( Roma)
Massenet, Jules, 1842-1912 ( Scènes alsacienes)
Massenet, Jules, 1842-1912 ( Scènes hongroises)
Massenet, Jules, 1842-1912 ( Scènes napolitaines)
Massenet, Jules, 1842-1912 ( Soir de printemps)
Massenet, Jules, 1842-1912 ( Suite parnassienne)
Massenet, Jules, 1842-1912 ( Suite théâtrale)
Massenet, Jules, 1842-1912 ( Terre promise)
Massenet, Jules, 1842-1912 ( Thérèse)
Massenet, Jules, 1842-1912 ( Vierge)
Maugham, Robin, 1916-1981 ( Somerset and all the Maughams)
Mendelssohn-Bartholdy, Felix, 1809-1847 ( Abschied)
Mendelssohn-Bartholdy, Felix, 1809-1847 ( Concertos, piano, orchestra, no. 2, op. 40, D minor)
Mendelssohn-Bartholdy, Felix, 1809-1847 ( Gesänge, op. 19a, Gruss)
Mendelssohn-Bartholdy, Felix, 1809-1847 ( Gesänge, op. 19A, Winterlied)
Mendelssohn-Bartholdy, Felix, 1809-1847 ( Auf Wiedersehn)
Mendelssohn-Bartholdy, Felix, 1809-1847 ( Lieder ohne Worte, piano, op. 85, Nr. 5)
Mendelssohn-Bartholdy, Felix, 1809-1847 ( Laudate pueri)
Mendelssohn-Bartholdy, Felix, 1809-1847 ( Oedipus in Kolonos, Zur rossprangenden Flur)
Mendelssohn-Bartholdy, Felix, 1809-1847 ( Verleih uns Frieden gnädiglich, arranged)
Menotti, Gian Carlo, 1911-2007 ( Canti della lontananza, Dorme Pegaso)
Milhaud, Darius, 1892-1974 ( Mother courage)
Miller, Henry, 1891-1980 ( Tropic of Cancer)
Milne, A. A. (Alan Alexander), 1882-1956 ( When we were very young)
Morlacchi, Francesco, 1784-1841 ( Rosa appassita)
Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791 ( Gavottes, orchestra, K. 300, B♭ major)
Offenbach, Jacques, 1819-1880 ( Amour chanteur)
Offenbach, Jacques, 1819-1880 ( Apothicaire et perruquier)
Offenbach, Jacques, 1819-1880 ( Après le jour)
Offenbach, Jacques, 1819-1880 ( Baguette)
Offenbach, Jacques, 1819-1880 ( Barbablù)
Offenbach, Jacques, 1819-1880 ( Barbier de Séville)
Offenbach, Jacques, 1819-1880 ( Boîte au lait)
Offenbach, Jacques, 1819-1880 ( Choruses, Selections)
Offenbach, Jacques, 1819-1880 ( Concerto militaire)
Offenbach, Jacques, 1819-1880 ( Contes d'Hoffmann)
Offenbach, Jacques, 1819-1880 ( Dance music, Selections)
Offenbach, Jacques, 1819-1880 ( Décaméron)
Offenbach, Jacques, 1819-1880 ( Duchesse d'Albe)
Offenbach, Jacques, 1819-1880 ( Élodie, Romance du Charcutier, arranged)
Offenbach, Jacques, 1819-1880 ( Entrez, messieurs, mesdames)
Offenbach, Jacques, 1819-1880 ( Fantasio)
Offenbach, Jacques, 1819-1880 ( Fifre enchanté)
Offenbach, Jacques, 1819-1880 ( Foire Saint-Laurent)
Offenbach, Jacques, 1819-1880 ( Geneviève de Brabant)
Offenbach, Jacques, 1819-1880 ( Géorgiennes)
Offenbach, Jacques, 1819-1880 ( Jolie parfumeuse)
Offenbach, Jacques, 1819-1880 ( Conversation alsacienne)
Offenbach, Jacques, 1819-1880 ( Madame Favart)
Offenbach, Jacques, 1819-1880 ( Madame l'Archiduc)
Offenbach, Jacques, 1819-1880 ( Mariage de Figaro)
Offenbach, Jacques, 1819-1880 ( Damen auf dem Markt)
Offenbach, Jacques, 1819-1880 ( Orchestra music, Selections)
Offenbach, Jacques, 1819-1880 ( Fées du Rhin)
Offenbach, Jacques, 1819-1880 ( Robinson Crusoé)
Offenbach, Jacques, 1819-1880 ( Roi Carotte)
Offenbach, Jacques, 1819-1880 ( Songs, Selections)
Offenbach, Jacques, 1819-1880 ( 4 Impressionen)
Pacini, Giovanni, 1796-1867 ( Songs, Selections)
Pergolesi, Giovanni Battista, 1710-1736 ( Fenice sul rogo)
Ponchielli, Amilcare, 1834-1886 ( Omaggio a Donizetti)
Poulenc, Francis, 1899-1963 ( Animaux modèles)
Poulenc, Francis, 1899-1963 ( Banalités)
Poulenc, Francis, 1899-1963 ( Biches)
Poulenc, Francis, 1899-1963 ( Flute player lullabies the ruins)
Poulenc, Francis, 1899-1963 ( Matelote provençale)
Poulenc, Francis, 1899-1963 ( Mélancolie)
Poulenc, Francis, 1899-1963 ( Sonatas, flute, piano)
Poulenc, Francis, 1899-1963 ( Encores)
Proust, Marcel, 1871-1922 ( À la recherche du temps perdu)
Proust, Marcel, 1871-1922 ( À l'ombre des jeunes filles en fleurs)
Proust, Marcel, 1871-1922 ( À la recherche du temps perdu, 3, Côté de Guermantes)
Proust, Marcel, 1871-1922 ( À la recherche du temps perdu, Du côté de chez Swann)
Proust, Marcel, 1871-1922 ( Plaisirs et les jours)
Proust, Marcel, 1871-1922 ( Prisonnière)
Puccini, Giacomo, 1858-1924 ( Fanciulla del West)
Puccini, Giacomo, 1858-1924 ( Chio-Chio-San)
Puccini, Giacomo, 1858-1924 ( Tosca)
Puccini, Giacomo, 1858-1924 ( Turandot)
Radiguet, Raymond, 1903-1923 ( Bal du comte d'Orgel)
Radiguet, Raymond, 1903-1923 ( Joues en feu)
Ravel, Maurice, 1875-1937 ( À la manière de .…, Borodine)
Ravel, Maurice, 1875-1937 ( À la manière de ... Chabrier)
Ravel, Maurice, 1875-1937 ( Berceuse sur le nom de Fauré)
Ravel, Maurice, 1875-1937 ( Grand sommeil noir)
Ravel, Maurice, 1875-1937 ( 4 orchestral works)
Ravel, Maurice, 1875-1937 ( Album for piano solo)
Ravel, Maurice, 1875-1937 ( Sites auriculaires)
Ravel, Maurice, 1875-1937 ( Sonatas, violin, piano, no. 2)
Respighi, Ottorino, 1879-1936 ( Orchestra music, Selections)
Respighi, Ottorino, 1879-1936 ( 6 composizioni inedite)
Respighi, Ottorino, 1879-1936 ( Re Enzo)
Respighi, Ottorino, 1879-1936 ( Songs, Selections)
Robert, Louis de, 1871-1937 ( Papa)
Rossini, Gioacchino, 1792-1868 ( Cantata for Francis I's visit)
Rossini, Gioacchino, 1792-1868 ( Scherzos, piano, A minor)
Roussel, Albert, 1869-1937 ( Padmâvatî)
Roussel, Albert, 1869-1937 ( Aunt Caroline's will)
Rubinstein, Anton, 1829-1894 ( Quartets, violins (2), viola, cello, op. 106, No. 1)
Saint-Saëns, Camille, 1835-1921 ( Ancêtre)
Saint-Saëns, Camille, 1835-1921 ( Elegies, violin, piano, op. 143, D major)
Saint-Saëns, Camille, 1835-1921 ( Promised land)
Saint-Saëns, Camille, 1835-1921 ( Trios, piano, strings, no. 1, op. 18, F major)
Satie, Erik, 1866-1925 ( Parade, arranged)
Satie, Erik, 1866-1925 ( Carillon)
Schubert, Franz, 1797-1828 ( Fantasia, piano, 4 hands, D. 940, F minor)
Schubert, Franz, 1797-1828 ( 100 songs)
Schumann, Clara, 1819-1896 ( Variationen über ein Thema von Robert Schumann)
Schumann, Robert, 1810-1856 ( Fest-Ouverture, arranged)
Schumann, Robert, 1810-1856 ( 3 Jugendlieder)
Sibelius, Jean, 1865-1957 ( Lieder)
Sterling, George, 1869-1926 ( Lilith)
Straus, Oscar, 1870-1954 ( Encanto de un vals)
Strauss, Richard, 1864-1949 ( 3 Liebeslieder)
Stravinsky, Igor, 1882-1971 ( Baĭka)
Stravinsky, Igor, 1882-1971 ( 5 easy pieces)
Stravinsky, Igor, 1882-1971 ( Etudes, pianola)
Piave, Francesco Maria, 1810-1876 ( Ernani)
Villa-Lobos, Heitor ( Fantasia de movimentos mistos, arranged)
Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883 ( Lohengrin, Libretto)
Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883 ( Chant de concours)
Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883 ( Ring des Nibelungen, Götterdämmerung, Libretto)
Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883 ( Songs, Selections)
Walton, William, 1902-1983 ( Anniversary fanfare)
Walton, William, 1902-1983 ( Anon in love)
Walton, William, 1902-1983 ( Antiphon)
Walton, William, 1902-1983 ( As you like it)
Walton, William, 1902-1983 ( Ballets, Selections)
Walton, William, 1902-1983 ( Band music, Selections)
Walton, William, 1902-1983 ( Battle of Britain)
Walton, William, 1902-1983 ( Bär)
Walton, William, 1902-1983 ( Cantico del sole)
Walton, William, 1902-1983 ( Capriccio burlesco)
Walton, William, 1902-1983 ( Choral music, Selections)
Walton, William, 1902-1983 ( Concertos, viola, orchestra)
Walton, William, 1902-1983 ( Concertos, violin, orchestra)
Walton, William, 1902-1983 ( Concertos, cello, orchestra)
Walton, William, 1902-1983 ( Coronation Te Deum)
Walton, William, 1902-1983 ( Coronation march)
Walton, William, 1902-1983 ( Duets for children)
Walton, William, 1902-1983 ( Escape me never)
Walton, William, 1902-1983 ( Façade (Entertainment))
Walton, William, 1902-1983 ( Façade (Suite no. 2))
Walton, William, 1902-1983 ( Fanfare for the National)
Walton, William, 1902-1983 ( Gloria)
Walton, William, 1902-1983 ( Hamlet)
Walton, William, 1902-1983 ( Henry V)
Walton, William, 1902-1983 ( Improvisations on an impromptu of Benjamin Britten)
Walton, William, 1902-1983 ( Incidental music, Selections)
Walton, William, 1902-1983 ( Chamber music)
Walton, William, 1902-1983 ( Johannesburg festival overture)
Walton, William, 1902-1983 ( Jubilate Deo)
Walton, William, 1902-1983 ( King Herod and the cock)
Walton, William, 1902-1983 ( Drop drop slow tears)
Walton, William, 1902-1983 ( March for A history of the English speaking peoples)
Walton, William, 1902-1983 ( Missa brevis)
Walton, William, 1902-1983 ( Music for children)
Walton, William, 1902-1983 ( Collected works)
Walton, William, 1902-1983 ( Partita, orchestra)
Walton, William, 1902-1983 ( Passacaglias, cello)
Walton, William, 1902-1983 ( Piano music, Selections)
Walton, William, 1902-1983 ( Portsmouth Point)
Walton, William, 1902-1983 ( Quartets, strings, no. 1)
Walton, William, 1902-1983 ( Quartets, strings, no. 2, A minor)
Walton, William, 1902-1983 ( Quest)
Walton, William, 1902-1983 ( Richard III)
Walton, William, 1902-1983 ( Scapino)
Walton, William, 1902-1983 ( Siesta)
Walton, William, 1902-1983 ( Sinfonia concertante, piano, orchestra)
Walton, William, 1902-1983 ( Sonatas, string orchestra, A minor)
Walton, William, 1902-1983 ( Song for the Lord Mayor's table)
Walton, William, 1902-1983 ( 4 early songs)
Walton, William, 1902-1983 ( First of the few, Prelude and fugue)
Walton, William, 1902-1983 ( Symphonies, no. 1)
Walton, William, 1902-1983 ( Symphonies, no. 2)
Walton, William, 1902-1983 ( Toccata, violin, piano)
Walton, William, 1902-1983 ( Troilus & Cressida)
Walton, William, 1902-1983 ( Anthem for the feast of any apostle)
Walton, William, 1902-1983 ( Hindemith variations)
Wilde, Oscar, 1854-1900 ( De profundis)
Wolf, Hugo, 1860-1903 ( Beherzigung)
Wolf, Hugo, 1860-1903 ( Ausgewählte Lieder)
Wolf-Ferrari, Ermanno, 1876-1948 ( Amanti sposi)
Wolf-Ferrari, Ermanno, 1876-1948 ( Cenerentola)
Wolf-Ferrari, Ermanno, 1876-1948 ( Chamber music, Selections)
Wolf-Ferrari, Ermanno, 1876-1948 ( Choral music, Selections)
Wolf-Ferrari, Ermanno, 1876-1948 ( Concertos, cello, orchestra, op. 31, C major)
Wolf-Ferrari, Ermanno, 1876-1948 ( Dama boba)
Wolf-Ferrari, Ermanno, 1876-1948 ( Curious women)
Wolf-Ferrari, Ermanno, 1876-1948 ( Gioielli della Madonna)
Wolf-Ferrari, Ermanno, 1876-1948 ( Irene)
Wolf-Ferrari, Ermanno, 1876-1948 ( Music of Wolf-Ferrari)
Wolf-Ferrari, Ermanno, 1876-1948 ( Orchestra music, Selections)
Wolf-Ferrari, Ermanno, 1876-1948 ( Organ music, Selections)
Wolf-Ferrari, Ermanno, 1876-1948 ( Piano music, Selections)
Wolf-Ferrari, Ermanno, 1876-1948 ( 4 peasants)
Wolf-Ferrari, Ermanno, 1876-1948 ( Secret de Suzanne)
Wolf-Ferrari, Ermanno, 1876-1948 ( Legend of the reawakened sleeper)
Wolf-Ferrari, Ermanno, 1876-1948 ( Songs, Selections)
Wolf-Ferrari, Ermanno, 1876-1948 ( Suite-concertino)
Wolf-Ferrari, Ermanno, 1876-1948 ( Cunning widow)
Wolf-Ferrari, Ermanno, 1876-1948 ( Vocal music, Selections)
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Deposited by the Frederick R. Koch Foundation, 1996. Gift of the Frederick R. Koch Foundation, 2001. Gift of Frederick R. Koch (Yale 1961 MFA), 2001.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Boxes 358-362: Restricted fragile material. Reference surrogates have been substituted in the main files. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
Scope and Contents
The Frederick R. Koch Collection consists of musical, literary, and historical materials collected by Frederick R. Koch (Yale School of Drama, 1961 MFAD), principally through purchases at public auctions, 1979-1986. Including individual items, concentrations of related materials, and several extensive archives, the collection is a broad and deep resource for study of the lives and works of a range of composers, authors, and other historical figures.
Most materials are music manuscripts, literary manuscripts, drawings, and correspondence of European, English, and American composers, authors, and artists. Also present are historical manuscripts, photographs, albums, and other papers. While the contents of the collection span the seventeenth to twentieth centuries, most date from the nineteenth to early twentieth centuries, with particular strengths in French, Italian, German, and British music, French literature, and British art.
The collection is organized alphabetically by name. Within each name, materials are organized under one or more of the following subheadings: Correspondence, Music, Writings, Drawings, and Other Papers. Bound and oversize materials are listed under the appropriate subheading but stored in one of the following shelving locations: volumes, volumes shelved flat, oversize volumes, folders shelved flat, oversize folders, or broadsides.
Correspondence is present for most names represented in the collection, and consists of outgoing letters arranged by name of recipient, unless otherwise noted. Within each recipient, correspondence is arranged chronologically.
Music is suborganized alphabetically by work title and arranged chronologically within each work. Folder titles identify the part of the work represented, if less than the full work, and the version of the work, type of composition, and medium of performance, if these are not clear from the work title. Arrangements of music by others and unidentified music, if present, are listed at the end of each composer's music. Unless otherwise noted, music is in the composer's holograph and score format is full score.
Among composers represented are: Hector Berlioz ( Roi Lear, other music, letters); Gerald Hugh Tyrwhitt-Wilson, Baron Berners ( The Triumph of Neptune ); Georges Bizet (letters to the Halévy family and others); Luigi Boccherini ( Quintets, piano, strings, G. 413-418 ); Johannes Brahms ( Alte Liebe and choral music); Claude Debussy ( Pelléas et Mélisande, other music, letters to Rosalie Texier and others); Henri Duparc (songs); Manual de Falla (music, letters to Georges Jean-Aubry and others); Gabriel Fauré (songs, chamber music, letters); César Franck ( Les béatitudes, other music); Charles Gounod ( Le médecine malgré lui, George Dandin, other music, letters); Reynaldo Hahn (music, diaries, letters); Fromental Halévy (letters, music); George Frideric Handel (church music composed in Rome, 1707, in copyist's manuscript); Ruggiero Leoncavallo (extensive opera manuscripts, letters); Franz Liszt (letters, music); Pietro Mascagni (operas, cantatas, letters to family); Jules Massenet (letters, extensive music including operas, oratorios, orchestral music, and songs); Felix Mendelssohn-Bartholdy (piano part for Concerto, piano, orchestra, no. 2, op. 40, D minor, songs and choral music, letter to Fanny Mendelssohn Hensel, letters to others); Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart ( Gavotte, orchestra, K. 300, B-flat major ); Jacques Offenbach (extensive opera manuscripts, including Les contes d'Hoffmann, other music, letters); Giovanni Battista Pergolesi ( La fenice sul rogo ); Francis Poulenc ( Les biches, Banalités, other music, photographs, letters to Pierre Bernac, Georges and Nora Auric, and others); Giacomo Puccini (opera fragments, family correspondence, letters to Angelo Magrini, Alfredo Vandini, and others); Maurice Ravel (music, letters to Roland-Manuel, the Godebski family, and others); Ottorino Respighi (songs, transcriptions, other music, letters); Camille Saint-Saëns ( The Promised Land, other music, letters to Émile Renaud and others); Erik Satie ( Parade, other music, letters); Franz Schubert ( Fantasie, piano, 4 hand, D. 940, F minor, songs); Richard Strauss (songs, letters, photographs); Igor Stravinsky ( Baika, piano music); Giuseppi Verdi (libretto for Ernani, more than 200 letters to Opprandino Arrivabene, Francesco Maria Piave, and others); Richard Wagner (libretti for Lohengrin and Götterdämmerung, songs, letters); William Walton (nearly complete music archive); Carl Maria von Weber (letters to Gottfried Weber); Hugo Wolf (songs, letters); and Ermanno Wolf-Ferrari (extensive operas, other music, letters).
Writings are arranged alphabetically by work title, followed by unidentified material. Most writings are by literary authors; also present are writings by musicians and others. Unless otherwise noted, manuscripts are in the author's holograph.
Authors include W. H. Auden (early letters); William Beckford (letters to George Clark); Jean Cocteau (extensive letters, manuscripts, drawings); Noel Coward (complete diaries, fragments of other writings); Alphonse Daudet ( L'Arlésienne ); Jean Genet ( Les bonnes, other writings); Henry James (letters to many correspondents); Edward Lear ( A Book of Nonsense, other writings, letters); Anita Loos (fragments of an unidentified play, letters); Henry Miller ( Tropic of Cancer ); A. A. Milne ( When We Were Very Young, letters); Marcel Proust (fragments and proofs for A l'ombre des jeunes filles en fleurs and Le côté de Guermantes, other writings, letters to Reynaldo Hahn, Daniel Halévy, Jeanne Weill Proust, and many others); Arthur Rimbaud (letters to family); Paul Verlaine (letters, poems, other writings); and Oscar Wilde (letters, poem, and typescripts of De Profundis ).